#### Resume

# Mahesh Vaidya Forvaidya@gmail.com / 9740500144

## **Professional Summary**

An accomplished Devops / SRE engineer with hands on coding and administration experience, a quick learner and go-to person. I have multi years of experience in Devops (and Release Engineering then) in the domains Retail, Telecom and Fintech.

## Skills and capabilities

Programming Languages: C, Python, Golang, Perl and Java, rust, node.js

Operating Systems: Linux (RHEL, Debian, Ubuntu) and Windows.

Tools: Git, Github, Jenkins, AzureDevops (TFS), maven, gradle, npm,

Containerization: Docker

IAAS: Ansible, Terraform, CDK/Pulumi

Networking / Protocols: TCP, SSH, HTTP(S), PKI, Certificates, DNS etc.

Frontend Frameworks and technologies: NodeJS, Django, Golang – Martini, Fiber etc.

Orchestration: Kubernetes (EKS/GKE/OnPrem), Helm, Docker Compose

### Work Experience

Platform Engineer – Flipkart Internet private limited, Bangalore April 7, 2022 – till date.

- Working in central platform group looking after GCP administration, K8S administration and platform engineering portfolio. Typical day job contains -
- GCP administration user provisioning, security, VPC SVC controls and cost controls.
- K8S operational support, namespace creation, monitoring, stateless K8S deployment for workloads relating to Platform Engineering.
- Hadoop, Spark Support in Flipkart Data Platform
- Development of tools in Golang and Python.

Devops Architect – Philips – Bangalore

11-Nov-2019 to 6 April, 2022.

- Code Repository / Build Pipelines Azure Devops CI/CD pipelines.
- Designing templates for common constructs like SEMVER in azure devops pipelines
- Developing Terraform scripts for EKS deployment
- Deploying microservices on Cloud-Foundry and EKS
- Liaising with central IT for production deployment, getting SSL certificates etc.
- General automation in Python, GoLang and Powershell
- Support Legacy SCM system IBM/Rational Clearcase

Devops Engineer – Adva Optical Networking – Bangalore

August 2016 – November 2019

General Release Engineering architecture and support for SDN, SDWAN product division.

- Gerrit, Jira, Jenkins
- Perl, Python, Bash, MySQL
- General coding support.

Owner / Promoter – Awanitron Technologies pvt ltd – Bangalore

Oct 2012 - August 2016.

Self employed, Devops and Release Engineering consultancy.

- Major Client TPVision (erstwhile Philips TV division).
- Gerrit, Python, Makefiles, C, Google AOSP build systems.

#### Several Other Jobs between 1997 – 2012

Mostly in the Release Engineering role.

Clearcase, SVN, CVS, perl, python, PHP, C, Makefiles etc.

Please refer to linkedin profile at <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gitbangalore/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/gitbangalore/</a>

#### Education

Master of Science (mechanical engineering) – IIT Bombay 1995

Bachelor of Engineering (production engineering) 1992

Location: Bangalore, India

Notice: 3 Months.

Visa: B1 Visa until 2030